<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>BloxWeaver Insights Blog</title><description>Get the latest updates from BloxWeaver Insights as they happen.</description><link>https://bloxweaver.com/</link><language>en-US</language><item><title>Introducing the BloxWeaver File Engineering Agent</title><link>https://bloxweaver.com/blog/introducing-the-file-engineering-agent/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://bloxweaver.com/blog/introducing-the-file-engineering-agent/</guid><description>Say goodbye to configuration bottlenecks. Our new AI agent generates file filter configurations instantly, letting localization teams move faster than ever.</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
    &lt;h3&gt;Introducing the BloxWeaver File Engineering Agent&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Every localization manager knows the frustration. A new file format lands on your desk—maybe it&apos;s a complex JSON with nested HTML, an Excel sheet with specific metadata requirements, or some proprietary format your development team just started using. The translation work stops. Everything waits while you manually configure file filters or, worse, submit a support ticket and wait days for your technical team to set things up. We built the BloxWeaver File Engineering Agent to end this bottleneck and hand the power back to you and your team. &amp;lt;div class=&quot;relative&quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div class=&quot;wistia_responsive_padding&quot; style=&quot;padding:56.25% 0 0 0;position:relative;&quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div class=&quot;wistia_responsive_wrapper&quot; style=&quot;height:100%;left:0;position:absolute;top:0;width:100%;&quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div class=&quot;wistia_embed wistia_async_y7n0exz31g seo=true videoFoam=true&quot; style=&quot;height:100%;position:relative;width:100%&quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div class=&quot;wistia_swatch&quot; style=&quot;height:100%;left:0;opacity:0;overflow:hidden;position:absolute;top:0;transition:opacity 200ms;width:100%;&quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&quot;https://fast.wistia.com/embed/medias/y7n0exz31g/swatch&quot; style=&quot;filter:blur(5px);height:100%;object-fit:contain;width:100%;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; onload=&quot;this.parentNode.style.opacity=1;&quot; /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;script src=&quot;https://fast.wistia.com/embed/medias/y7n0exz31g.jsonp&quot; async&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt; &amp;lt;script src=&quot;https://fast.wistia.com/assets/external/E-v1.js&quot; async&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; The Problem: Configuration Complexity Slows Teams Down In today&apos;s fast-moving environment, the content types you need to support evolve constantly. New systems are...&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bloxweaver.com/blog/introducing-the-file-engineering-agent/&quot;&gt;Read the full article on BloxWeaver Insights →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  </content:encoded><category>AI</category><category>Localization</category><category>File Engineering</category><category>Product Launch</category><author>BloxWeaver Team</author></item><item><title>Discussing Leadership and AI on MBN&apos;s A Class Act Podcast</title><link>https://bloxweaver.com/blog/a-class-act-podcast/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://bloxweaver.com/blog/a-class-act-podcast/</guid><description>Our founder David Meikle joins Shannon McKechnie on MBN Solution&apos;s A Class Act podcast for a wide-ranging conversation covering Leadership and Artificial Intelligence.</description><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
    &lt;h3&gt;Discussing Leadership and AI on MBN&apos;s A Class Act Podcast&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We were delighted to join Shannon McKechnie on MBN Solution&apos;s podcast, A Class Act: Conversations in Data and Leadership. On the podcast our founder, David Meikle, reflects on the leadership lessons he learned introducing AI and automation into the translation industry nearly ten years before most businesses began facing the same challenges. It was a wide-ranging conversation covering the following main topics: How to lead teams through fear of AI and show its value. Why psychological safety is essential for innovation and high performance. How David rebuilt trust after leading a restructure early in his career. The leadership principles behind scaling from 12% to 98% online orders in a year. Why patience, adaptability, and strengths-based leadership matter most in change. You can find the episode on: Spotify Apple Podcasts YouTube&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bloxweaver.com/blog/a-class-act-podcast/&quot;&gt;Read the full article on BloxWeaver Insights →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  </content:encoded><category>Podcast</category><category>AI</category><category>Leadership</category><author>David Meikle</author></item><item><title>BloxWeaver Featured in Slator&apos;s Language AI 50 Under 50</title><link>https://bloxweaver.com/blog/bloxweaver-in-slator-language-ai-50-under-50/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://bloxweaver.com/blog/bloxweaver-in-slator-language-ai-50-under-50/</guid><description>We&apos;re thrilled to share that BloxWeaver has been included in Slator&apos;s 2025 Language AI 50 Under 50 list, showcasing fifty of the most innovative language AI companies founded in the last 50 months.</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
    &lt;h3&gt;BloxWeaver Featured in Slator&apos;s Language AI 50 Under 50&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We&apos;re thrilled to share that BloxWeaver has been included in Slator&apos;s 2025 Language AI 50 Under 50, showcasing fifty of the most innovative and fast-growing language AI companies founded within the last 50 months. Slator, the leading industry publication covering language services and technology, selected BloxWeaver as part of their 2025 cohort highlighting companies that are &quot;showing increasing differentiation&quot; and &quot;emerging as vertical specialists, moving beyond core language functionalities to deliver &apos;whole product&apos; experiences.&quot; It specifically mentions BloxWeaver&apos;s mission to &quot;eliminate localization friction with end-to-end content services that support multimodal formats, model fine-tuning, and workflow agents.&quot; This recognition comes at an exciting time for the language AI industry. As Slator notes, this year&apos;s startups &quot;couldn&apos;t be further from generic translation tools or prompt-based LLM outputs. Instead of one-size-fits-all text translation and generation, they offer structured control, integrated workflows, and business-specific capabilities.&quot; What a journey it&apos;s been since launching last year,...&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bloxweaver.com/blog/bloxweaver-in-slator-language-ai-50-under-50/&quot;&gt;Read the full article on BloxWeaver Insights →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  </content:encoded><category>News</category><category>Language AI</category><category>Slator</category><category>AI</category><author>David Meikle</author></item><item><title>The Precision Content Series: Context Enrichment</title><link>https://bloxweaver.com/blog/context-enrichment/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://bloxweaver.com/blog/context-enrichment/</guid><description>Explore Context Enrichment - the intelligence layer that transforms good translations into great ones. Learn how rich contextual information enables nuanced decision-making in precision content localization.</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
    &lt;h3&gt;The Precision Content Series: Context Enrichment&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Welcome back to The Precision Content Series, where we explore the essential pillars that enable organizations to deliver precision content at global scale. In our previous posts, we introduced the concept of precision content and examined the critical foundation of Content Processing and Filtering. Today, we turn our attention to what many consider the most transformative pillar: Context Enrichment. Context Enrichment represents the difference between good and great translation. It involves identifying and leveraging appropriate contextual information - whether actively integrated into translation production or provided as reference material to guide human translators and AI models toward more accurate, culturally appropriate outcomes. Building on the content processing capabilities we explored previously, context enrichment extends far beyond the immediate content being translated, drawing from multiple sources to create a rich understanding that enables truly precision localization. This includes dynamic enrichment techniques that leverage relationships within content, external knowledge sources, and even...&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bloxweaver.com/blog/context-enrichment/&quot;&gt;Read the full article on BloxWeaver Insights →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  </content:encoded><category>Precision Content</category><category>Context Enrichment</category><category>Translation</category><category>Localization</category><category>AI</category><author>David Meikle</author></item><item><title>The Precision Content Series: Content Processing and Filtering</title><link>https://bloxweaver.com/blog/content-processing-and-filtering/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://bloxweaver.com/blog/content-processing-and-filtering/</guid><description>Explore the often unsung hero of quality localisation: Content Processing and Filtering. Learn how what happens before your content reaches translators can dramatically impact quality, efficiency, and cost.</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
    &lt;h3&gt;The Precision Content Series: Content Processing and Filtering&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Welcome back to The Precision Content Series - our focus on the key areas that help deliver precision content. In our previous post, we introduced what we mean by precision content and outlined the five pillars required to achieve it: Content Processing and Filtering Context Enrichment Content Workbench Model Selection and Optimization Subject Matter Expertise and Review Today, we spotlight the often unsung hero of quality localisation: Content Processing and Filtering. While most organizations often focus much of their effort on translation mechanics, what happens before your content reaches translators or AI systems can dramatically impact quality, efficiency, and cost. This crucial first step involves deciding what content to include or exclude for translation, identifying or generating additional context, and determining what adaptations are required before or after translation. Why Content Processing Matters Consider the scenario, a global e-commerce company needs to translate its product catalog into 36 languages. At...&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bloxweaver.com/blog/content-processing-and-filtering/&quot;&gt;Read the full article on BloxWeaver Insights →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  </content:encoded><category>Precision Content</category><category>Content Processing</category><category>Localization</category><category>Translation</category><category>Automation</category><category>AI</category><author>David Meikle</author></item><item><title>The Precision Content Series: What is Precision Content?</title><link>https://bloxweaver.com/blog/what-is-precision-content/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://bloxweaver.com/blog/what-is-precision-content/</guid><description>An introduction to precision content and why high-value materials require meticulous attention to linguistic nuance, cultural context, and technical accuracy during translation and localization.</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
    &lt;h3&gt;The Precision Content Series: What is Precision Content?&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Over the past ten years, content creation and distribution have reached unprecedented scales. This expansion, driven by the increasing global nature of modern business, has brought both new opportunities and significant challenges in maintaining quality across languages and cultures. The rise of AI technologies, particularly in translation and localization, has created a complex landscape of possibilities and pitfalls. While AI has been part of the translation industry longer than most - with the original Transformer model designed specifically for machine translation - today&apos;s environment of heightened AI awareness has created new dynamics. Many vendors have leaned into the current AI hype cycle, emphasising large language models and automated solutions that promise quick, cheap translations. However, for organisations with high-value content, this approach often falls short of delivering the required quality and precision. For organisations with high-value content, we need to think differently. We define &apos;precision content&apos; as materials that require...&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bloxweaver.com/blog/what-is-precision-content/&quot;&gt;Read the full article on BloxWeaver Insights →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  </content:encoded><category>Precision Content</category><category>Translation</category><category>Localization</category><category>AI</category><category>Content Strategy</category><author>David Meikle</author></item><item><title>AI-Driven Content Management and Multilingual Strategies on The Lucent Perspective</title><link>https://bloxweaver.com/blog/lucent-perspective-podcast/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://bloxweaver.com/blog/lucent-perspective-podcast/</guid><description>Our founder David Meikle joins Rebecca Hastings on The Lucent Perspective podcast for a wide-ranging conversation covering content management, AI customisation, and preparing companies for exits.</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
    &lt;h3&gt;AI-Driven Content Management and Multilingual Strategies on The Lucent Perspective&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We were delighted to join Rebecca Hastings on her podcast, The Lucent Perspective for a wide ranging conversation covering content management, AI customisation, and preparing companies for exits. On the podcast our founder, David Meikle, shared his expertise on leveraging AI to tackle multilingual content management, a challenge many global companies face today. He shared a deep dive into &quot;content fabric&quot; and how it is reshaping enterprise content strategies. It was a wide ranging conversation covering the following main topics: Challenges in multilingual content management AI applications in language technology The concept of &quot;content fabric&quot; for global businesses Customizing AI for enterprise success Benefits of open-source contributions to career development Preparing companies for exits from a CTO&apos;s perspective Give it a listen if you&apos;re curious about how AI is shaping the future of content, and let us know your thoughts. Thanks again to Rebecca for the great conversation! You can...&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bloxweaver.com/blog/lucent-perspective-podcast/&quot;&gt;Read the full article on BloxWeaver Insights →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  </content:encoded><category>Podcast</category><category>AI</category><category>Content Management</category><category>Multilingual</category><author>David Meikle</author></item></channel></rss>